List<Map<String, dynamic>> oRPartTwoQuestions = [
  {
    'question': 'Which type of surgery involves the removal of a segment of a lung or a whole lung?',
    'answers': ['Lobectomy.', 'Pneumonectomy.', 'Tracheostomy.', 'Bronchoscopy',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'During a craniotomy, which type of saw is often used to cut through bone?',
    'answers': ['Coping saw.', 'Oscillating saw.', 'Hacksaw.', 'Miter saw',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'In surgery, what is the term for the complete separation of wound edges, exposing underlying tissues?',
    'answers': ['Evisceration.', 'Dehiscence.', 'Incision.', 'Perforation',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'Which specialized nurse is responsible for managing the sterile field and surgical instruments during surgery?',
    'answers': ['Scrub nurse.', 'Circulating nurse.', 'Anesthesia nurse.', 'Recovery nurse',],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What type of anesthesia is typically used for a patient who needs to remain awake and alert during surgery on a limb?',
    'answers': ['General anesthesia.', 'Epidural anesthesia.', 'Local anesthesia.', 'Spinal anesthesia',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'During a laparotomy, what is the purpose of a retractor?',
    'answers': ['To cut through tissue.', 'To hold back the edges of an incision.', 'To provide illumination.', 'To seal blood vessels',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'Which of the following is NOT a component of the "sterile corridor" in the operating room?',
    'answers': ['Surgical table.', 'Mayo stand.', 'Instrument tray.', 'Anesthesia machine',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the term for a surgical procedure that involves the removal of a kidney?',
    'answers': ['Hysterectomy.', 'Nephrectomy.', 'Appendectomy.', 'Splenectomy',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary purpose of a surgical gown and gloves for the surgical team?',
    'answers': ['Enhancing dexterity.', 'Comfort.', 'Infection control.', 'Fashion',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'Which surgical procedure is performed to create an opening in the trachea to assist with breathing?',
    'answers': ['Tracheostomy.', 'Esophagogastroduodenoscopy.', 'Laryngoscopy.', 'Bronchoscopy',],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the term for a surgical procedure to remove the gallbladder?',
    'answers': ['Gastrectomy.', 'Appendectomy.', 'Cholecystectomy.', 'Colostomy',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'During a craniotomy, what type of instrument is used to remove bone and shape the skull opening?',
    'answers': ['Rongeur.', 'Gouge.', 'Osteotome.', 'Trephine',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What surgical instrument is used to hold back tissues or organs during a procedure?',
    'answers': ['Trocar.', 'Hemostat.', 'Retractor.', 'Scissors',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'Which surgical specialty focuses on the treatment of conditions involving the digestive system?',
    'answers': ['Urology.', 'Gynecology.', 'Gastroenterology.', 'Ophthalmology',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a surgical smoke evacuator in the operating room?',
    'answers': ['To maintain temperature.', 'To remove surgical smoke and odor.', 'To provide lighting.', 'To monitor vital signs',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'Which type of suture material is commonly used for delicate tissue and ophthalmic procedures?',
    'answers': ['Silk.', 'Nylon.', 'Vicryl.', 'Prolene',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'During abdominal surgery, which layer of tissue is often closed first during wound closure?',
    'answers': ['Skin.', 'Subcutaneous tissue.', 'Fascia.', 'Peritoneum',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'In orthopedic surgery, what is the term for the surgical repair of a bone fracture using hardware such as screws and plates?',
    'answers': ['Osteotomy.', 'Arthroscopy.', 'Internal fixation.', 'Exostosis',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a sequential compression device (SCD) in the operating room?',
    'answers': ['To monitor oxygen saturation.', 'To prevent blood clots in the legs.', 'To provide pain relief.', 'To maintain body temperature',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'During cataract surgery, which part of the eye is typically removed and replaced with an intraocular lens (IOL)?',
    'answers': ['Cornea.', 'Retina.', 'Lens.', 'Sclera',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'In plastic surgery, what is the term for the surgical removal of excess skin and fat from the abdomen?',
    'answers': ['Rhinoplasty.', 'Liposuction.', 'Abdominoplasty.', 'Facelift',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the term for a surgical procedure to remove the uterus?',
    'answers': ['Hysterectomy.', 'Oophorectomy.', 'Salpingectomy.', 'Myomectomy',],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question': 'During a laparoscopic procedure, what gas is commonly used to create a pneumoperitoneum?',
    'answers': ['Oxygen.', 'Nitrous oxide.', 'Carbon dioxide.', 'Helium',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What type of surgery is performed to remove a portion of the stomach for weight loss purposes?',
    'answers': ['Gastric bypass surgery.', 'Appendectomy.', 'Hernia repair.', 'Colostomy',],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question': 'Which surgical specialty focuses on the treatment of conditions involving the urinary system?',
    'answers': ['Nephrology.', 'Urology.', 'Gastroenterology.', 'Cardiology',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'During an appendectomy, which surgical instrument is commonly used to ligate the base of the appendix?',
    'answers': ['Hemostat.', 'Suction catheter.', 'Endoclip applier.', 'Electrocautery',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'In endoscopic surgery, what is the purpose of the insufflator?',
    'answers': ['To maintain oxygen saturation.', 'To control bleeding.', 'To create a clear visual field.', 'To monitor blood pressure',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the term for a surgical procedure to remove a part of the colon?',
    'answers': ['Colostomy.', 'Ileostomy.', 'Appendectomy.', 'Colectomy',],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a surgical smoke evacuation system?',
    'answers': ['To maintain oxygen saturation.', 'To remove harmful surgical smoke.', 'To provide lighting.', 'To monitor vital signs',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
];
